so hi I'm Joe Brewer and I'm a change
strategist today the book that I'd like
to review is this one the open
collaboration encyclopedia the essential
guide book of participatory culture
that's edited by alpha low and Elvin
Bevington and this is a book that
explains the various terms and
technologies that are used to create
open collaboration so just for those of
you who don't know open collaboration is
any process that involves a an open
community of people who can collaborate
collectively to create shared resources
or shared outcomes so a simple example
would be the Wikipedia website which is
a massive collaboration among
knowledgeable and educated people around
the world to each add little bits of
information to this repository of
knowledge that is now the largest
encyclopedia on the planet so this
process of having an open architecture
for a system to invite people to connect
with it and participate in ways that
lead to collect outcomes that is called
open collaboration and open
collaboration is the basis of things
like open source software which has
created the linux operating system a
number of software languages the
wordpress blogging software that's used
for creating websites easily and quickly
as well as a lot of the themes and
templates for making those websites
usable and beautiful but there are also
many other things like there are
organizing are ways of organizing events
or facilitating group activities so
things like hackathons and mashups and
open space which are all ways of
bringing together people which have a
shared vision or mission and help enable
ingham to create a shared agenda and
then create outcomes around that shared
agenda there's a lot of stuff in open
collaboration that is the basis for
crowdfunding for the sharing economy and
various forms of business models ways of
solving difficult problems that can't be
solved by individuals but require the
perspectives or people from many
different backgrounds to come together
and address them in this book the open
collaboration encyclopedia is actually
created using open source techniques so
this is a a book that was created with a
very large number of contributors adding
content in the same way that Wikipedia
built its huge repository a large number
of people added content to this and its
really a wonderful book it's constantly
being updated and to add new material to
it and I find it to just be an
incredible resource for anyone who wants
to understand how to create an open
participatory system so by the way that
includes things like 21st century
democracy or on social enterprises where
the business has the goal of creating
some positive social outcome but it
requires a high level of transparency
and accountability so really big
difficult challenges like how to have
work in government or having businesses
that do good and then are trustworthy
these kinds of challenges can be
addressed with open collaboration also
problems that are very difficult to
solve when people are separated from
each other information is hidden can be
solved by having large numbers of people
contribute to solving them and so this
open collaboration encyclopedia goes
through a lot of those tools techniques
methodologies frameworks concepts key
ideas and so forth it's really a
wonderful resource for anyone who wants
to encourage invite and effectively
implement collaboration processes that
lead to collective outcomes for large
groups of people so go get your copy
today put it on your shelf pull it out
any time that you need to find the right
tool or insight for whatever project
you're working on and make the world a
better place alright have a great day